Philip Bergman Papers
Philip Bergman Papers
1956-1995
Bergman, Philip S.
30 linear feet
Collection contains audio tape, videotape, film, personal papers, professional papers and photography related to ABC News producer and journalist Philip S. Bergman.
4640513
Biographical History
Philip Stewart Bergman was an American journalist and television news producer. Bergman spent the bulk of his professional career with ABC News, producing news documentaries and stories for a variety of programs including 20/20, Nightline, World News Tonight and the ABC Saturday Evening News with Ted Koppel.
Philip Bergman was born October 21, 1933 in New York, New York. After attending City College of New York, Bergman began his professional career as a reporter and editor at the Newark Star-Ledger and later worked as a reporter for United Press International. Bergman did a short stint in the U.S. Army (1957-1958) where he served as an Army correspondent. In 1962, Bergman joined ABC as a writer for WABC-TV News, and from 1964-1967 he produced WABC-TV's late night news program. In 1976, Bergman took the helm as Executive Producer for the ABC Saturday Evening News, beginning a working relationship with ABC anchor Ted Koppel that would last for many years. After several years as a Senior Producer for ABC's World News Tonight, where he supervised all feature and series shooting and editing--which included the "Special Assignment Series" and on the road segments with Hughes Rudd--Bergman went on to produce stories and segments for other prominent network news programs, including Nightline and 20/20. While serving as Senior Producer in the Long Form Documentary Unit at ABC (1988-1989), Bergman was involved in the production of "Burning Question: The Poisoning of America", an Emmy Award-winning news special on the state of the natural environment, investigating such issues as illegal dumping, air pollution, ozone depletion and acid rain.
Over the course of his long career, Phil Bergman won numerous awards including 5 national Emmy Awards, 2 national Headline Awards, a Christopher Award, and an Aviation and Space Writer's Award for Television and Radio. Phil Bergman was the brother of Jules Bergman, the ABC News Science Editor from 1961-1987 famous for his coverage of the American space program.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Philip Bergman Papers contains over 200 media items related to Bergman-produced television stories and segments (audio tape, film and videotape) and approximately 18 linear feet of papers, also primarily related to Bergman's professional television career and specific story and segment productions. A small portion of the papers and virtually all of the photography in the collection relates to Bergman's pre-television career as a print journalist, prior to joining ABC News.
Media items in the collection include audio tapes, film and videotapes. "Audio" tapes primarily contain original interviews done by Phil Bergman for television stories and segments and include original interviews with Muhammad Ali, Jimmy the Greek, Henry Kissinger and others. There are also audio interviews done for pieces on air safety and a New York City cop story done for 20/20. Additional audio tapes were collected to provide background information or as potential selections for segment soundtrack elements. The bulk of the "Moving image" items (videotape and film) in the collection are dub-recordings of Bergman-produced television segments and stories created for a variety of ABC News programs. There are also videotape and film items collected as background and research material, or for potential inclusion in produced pieces
Most of the materials in the Papers portion of the collection relate to Phil Bergman's professional career or to specific Bergman-produced stories and segments. The "Professional papers" material includes program binders, program research materials, reporter's notebooks, as well as general network communications and programming data. In addition to a small batch of personal correspondence, "Personal papers" also contains material related to Bergman's pre-television career, including writings and story ideas. Virtually all of the "Photography" relates to Bergman's time in college, in the military, and his pre-television days as a print journalist. "Memorabilia" in the collection includes press materials related to national political conventions (1964, 1976), the Reagan Inauguration (1981), the press kit for President Nixon's trip to Belgium in 1974, and various items Bergman collected over the course of his career at ABC News.
Arrangement of the Collection
Media items related to Philip Bergman-produced stories are sorted by type (audio and moving image) and grouped together according to related program, when known. Items with uncertain affiliation are grouped together under "Individual interviews" (audio) and "Individual Bergman pieces" (moving image). Research and background media items are grouped separately. The Papers are arranged as: Awards, Memorabilia, Personal papers, Photography, Professional papers and Reporters notebooks. Collection materials were rehoused from original containers but largely remain in original order. Most collection materials have not been re-foldered.
Other Related Finding Aids
Ted Koppel Collection
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; Radio, television, film; Bergman, Philip S.; ABC News.; 20/20 (Television program); ABC Saturday evening news (Television program); Nightline (Television program); ABC world news tonight (Television program); Broadcast journalism.; Documentary television programs.; Television broadcasting of news -- United States.; Television producers and directors.; Television news programs.; Audiotapes.; Correspondence.; Film reels.; Memorabilia.; Papers.; Phonograph records.; Photographs.; Videotapes.; Television producers and directors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Research access to the tapes requires advance notice in order to produce a working copy.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Jason Bergman, 2016.
Inventory
- Media, 1968-1995
  - Audio, 1968-1992
    - Air Crash story interviews
      - Air Crash TS755: Execs/Ken Burton (FC1-2), Audio; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_181 (Box 21)
      - Air Crash TS755: Execs Interviews (FC 2), Audio; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_182 (Box 21)
      - Air Crash TS755: Ken Burton (FC 4), Audio; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_183 (Box 21)
      - Air Crash: Witkowski Interview (14-15)/Coleman Interview (16), Audio; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 00:90:00; bergman_p_184 (Box 21)
      - Air Crash: Coleman Interview (17-18), Audio; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 00:90:00; bergman_p_185 (Box 21)
      - Air Crash TS755: Gus Sarkos, Audio; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_186 (Box 21)
      - Air Crash Safety: Gale Zukor (1-2), Audio; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_187 (Box 21)
      - Interview: Scott Jackson-Survivor 6/6/1992 (1A), Audio; 1/4 inch audio cassette; 00:45:00; bergman_p_188 (Box 21)
      - Air Crash Safety: Barbara Boxer Interview (1), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_189 (Box 21)
      - Air Safety: Stews Best End 20/20 (LA) (1)/Stews 20/20 (2), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_190 (Box 21)
      - Dave Koch Interview/Downs Stand Up/Dave Chittum Interview, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_191 (Box 21)
    - NY Cop story interviews
      - NYC Cop TS612: Queens Walk/Talk, 6/16/1990; Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:45:00; bergman_p_192 (Box 21)
      - NYC Cop TS612: Joy Ciarcia (Diane) (A-B), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_193 (Box 21)
      - NYC Cop TS612: Joy Ciarcia (Kuhn) (A-B), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:27:00; bergman_p_194 (Box 21)
      - NYC Cop TS612: Robert Biangazzo (20/20 Police Addicts) (1), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:45:00; bergman_p_195 (Box 21)
      - NYC Cop TS612: Robert Biangazzo (20/20 Police Addicts) (2), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:45:00; bergman_p_196 (Box 21)
      - NYC Cop TS612: Robert Biangazzo (20/20 Police Addicts) (4), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:45:00; bergman_p_197 (Box 21)
      - NYC Cop TS612: Robert Biangazzo (20/20 Police Addicts) (5), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:45:00; bergman_p_198 (Box 21)
    - Individual interviews
      - Muhammad Ali (Drew Bodeini) (1-2), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_199 (Box 21)
      - Ali (1-2), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_200 (Box 21)
      - Jimmy the Greek ("Use this on film"), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_201 (Box 21)
      - Jimmy the Greek Film Interview ("Use in film"), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_202 (Box 21)
      - Jimmy the Greek (Oct 68)/Johnny George, 10/1968; Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_203 (Box 21)
      - Kissinger (ABC Radio News), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_204 (Box 21)
      - Kissinger (ABC Radio News), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_205 (Box 21)
      - [Kissinger?] (ABC Radio News), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_206 (Box 21)
      - Clay-Marciano Filming (Humor), Audio; 1/4 inch audio tape; 00:20:00; bergman_p_207 (Box 21)
      - Marciano on Clay, Audio; 1/4 inch audio tape; 00:05:00; bergman_p_208 (Box 21)
      - P. Bergman Interview with Wayne Newton (1), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:45:00; bergman_p_209 (Box 21)
      - P. Bergman Interview with Wayne Newton, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_210 (Box 21)
      - Jay Sarno Roll No. 1 (Side 1-2), 1968; Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_211 (Box 21)
      - Jay Sarno Roll No. 2 (Side 1), 1968; Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_212 (Box 21)
      - Jay Sarno: Joey Boston/Caesers Circus, 1968; Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_213 (Box 21)
      - Dr. Siner II, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_214 (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous (unidentified)
      - Inter, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_215 (Box 21)
      - FBI, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_216 (Box 21)
      - Mon. Aug. 10, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_217 (Box 21)
      - W 9/23, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_218 (Box 21)
    - Research and background material
      - Wild Track Music and Background-Circus (Side 1) (Mayhew 69), 1969; Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_219 (Box 21)
      - New Madison Square Garden "Sounds of the Circus", Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_220 (Box 21)
      - David Rubitsky (ATC 891010), 10/10/1989; Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_221 (Box 21)
      - Don Rickles Friar's Roast, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_222 (Box 21)
      - Don Rickles Roast, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_223 (Box 21)
      - Howard Cosell Roast, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_224 (Box 21)
      - Las Vegas Songs, 10/24/1990; Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_225 (Box 21)
      - In Las Vegas Songs/America I Love You, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_226 (Box 21)
      - Drugs II - Music, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_227 (Box 21)
      - Drugs II (B), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_228 (Box 21)
      - Drop Kick Me Jesus Through the Goalpost of Life/Field Goal, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_229 (Box 21)
      - Music [Divorce songs], Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_230 (Box 21)
      - Prince Music, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_231 (Box 21)
      - America Held Hostage song, 1/3/1980; Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:30:00; bergman_p_232 (Box 21)
      - The Chocolate Song, Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:10:00; bergman_p_233 (Box 21)
      - When the North Pole Melts (Short Version)/When the North Pole Melts (Long Version), Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:10:00; bergman_p_234 (Box 21)
      - Blind Man's Zoo (10,000 Maniacs), 1989; Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_235 (Box 21)
      - Songs I Love to Sing (Slim Whitman), 1980; Audio; 1/8 inch audio cassette; 00:60:00; bergman_p_236 (Box 21)
  - Moving image, 1968-1995
    - 20/20 stories
      - Bungee, 10/16/1992; Videotape, Betacam-SP, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_001 (Box 10)
      - Divorce, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic SP, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_002 (Box 1)
      - Divorce (Screener), Videotape, Betacam, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_003 (Box 10)
      - Dog Divorce, Videotape, Betacam, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_004 (Box 10)
      - Pet Divorce (Sound Bite Pulls), Videotape, Betacam, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_005 (Box 10)
      - Extradition, 04/19/1991; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_006 (Box 10)
      - Extradition, 04/26/1991; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_007 (Box 10)
      - Friendly Fire (Conform Screener), 07/23/1992; Videotape, Betacam-SP, dub, 13:21; bergman_p_008 (Box 10)
      - Friendly Fire ("Death by Friendly Fire"), 08/28/1992; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_009 (Box 10)
      - HT Fighting, 12/08/1989; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_010 (Box 1)
      - Husbands and Breast Cancer (from show history), 04/07/1995; Videotape, Betacam-SP, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_011 (Box 10)
      - NYC Cop, 09/28/1990; Videotape, Betacam, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_012 (Box 10)
      - Tourists, 06/24/1994; Videotape, Betacam-SP, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_013 (Box 10)
      - Vocanelle Rape [?], Videotape, Betacam, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_014 (Box 10)
    - ABC Saturday Evening News stories
      - Koppel News Saturday (TK 2), 02/19/1977; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_015 (Box 1)
      - Ted Koppel Weekend News (TK 3), 02/26/1977; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_016 (Box 1)
      - Koppel News Saturday (TK 4), 03/05/1977; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_017 (Box 1)
      - Koppel News Saturday (TK 6), 03/19/1977; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_018 (Box 1)
      - Saturday Evening News (TK 10), 04/16/1977; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_019 (Box 1)
      - Weekend News (TK 30), 07/30/1977; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_020 (Box 1)
    - Hughes Rudd stories
      - 95 Year Old Baseball Player, 01/25/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_021 (Box 1)
      - Ali Tape Clips 1, 03/21/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, submaster, 30:00; bergman_p_022 (Box 1)
      - Ali Tape Clips 2, 03/21/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, submaster, 30:00; bergman_p_023 (Box 1)
      - Ali, 04/04/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_024 (Box 1)
      - Barn Painter (Mail Pouch Screening Copy) [1], 06/26/1982; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_025 (Box 1)
      - Barn Painter (Mail Pouch Screening Copy) [2], 06/26/1982; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_026 (Box 1)
      - Bells (Rudd)/Sadat (Harper) (Screening Copy Satellite), 07/01/1981; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_027 (Box 1)
      - Bells (with Peter Intro), 07/01/1981; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_028 (Box 1)
      - Bells (Emmy Winner) (Good Copy), 07/01/1981; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_029 (Box 1)
      - Bike/Carter/Priest, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_030 (Box 1)
      - Clown School (Mixed Dub) (For Air), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_031 (Box 2)
      - Dachau [1], 12/29/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_032 (Box 2)
      - Dachau [2], 12/29/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_033 (Box 2)
      - Dachau (Not for Air), 12/29/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_034 (Box 2)
      - Dead Celebs (Mixed Spot), 01/13/1983; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_035 (Box 2)
      - Detroit: I Want to Go Home (Spec), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_036 (Box 2)
      - Fireworks, 07/04/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_037 (Box 2)
      - Frogs (Frog College) (World News Tonight) [1], 04/12/1983; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 2:37; bergman_p_038 (Box 2)
      - Frogs (Frog College) (World News Tonight) [2], 04/12/1983; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 2:37; bergman_p_039 (Box 2)
      - Frogs (Frog College) (World News Tonight) [3], 04/12/1983; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 2:37; bergman_p_040 (Box 2)
      - Humor, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_041 (Box 2)
      - I Wouldn't Live in NYC (Mixed Show Spot), 08/10/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_042 (Box 2)
      - Jousting, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_043 (Box 2)
      - Kiteman, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_044 (Box 2)
      - Lady Di's Friends (GMA), 03/07/1981; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_045 (Box 2)
      - Make-up/Westmore, 11/21/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 4:30; bergman_p_046 (Box 2)
      - Miss Piggy (World News Tonight), 02/15/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_047 (Box 2)
      - Miss Piggy (Air Dub), 02/15/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_048 (Box 2)
      - Miss Piggy Interview, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_049 (Box 2)
      - Miss Piggy Interview (Full Interview Intercut), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_050 (Box 2)
      - Oddities (Edit Master) (Los Angeles 1984), 07/26/1984; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic SP, submaster, 10:00; bergman_p_051 (Box 3)
      - Ohio Castle (Edit Master), 11/09/1979; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, submaster, 20:00; bergman_p_052 (Box 3)
      - Ohio Castle (Mixed Dub), 11/09/1979; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_053 (Box 3)
      - Old Rip (The Horn Toad) (Final Cut) [1], 10/30/1979; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 3:35; bergman_p_054 (Box 3)
      - Old Rip (The Horn Toad) (Final Cut) [2], 10/30/1979; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 3:35; bergman_p_055 (Box 3)
      - Olympic Oddities (Edit Master) (Los Angeles 1984), 08/06/1984; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic SP, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_056 (Box 3)
      - One Man Band (GMA), 1984; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic SP, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_057 (Box 3)
      - One Man Band (Summer Olympics) (Dub w/ Ch.1 Mix) (Los Angeles 1984), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic SP, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_058 (Box 3)
      - One Man Band (Dub w/ Ch.1 Mix) (Los Angeles 1984), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic SP, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_059 (Box 3)
      - Polo (West Palm Beach), 04/18/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_060 (Box 3)
      - Pieces From Sarajevo Olympics: Slivovitz (2/7), Folk Music (2/10), Humor (2/19), 02/07/1984; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_061 (Box 3)
      - Reagan Coming In (Transition) (Not for Air: Screening Only), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 5:00; bergman_p_062 (Box 3)
      - Rudd Review (Los Angeles 1984), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic SP, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_063 (Box 3)
      - Sealands (Mixed) (Copy from 1"), 11/03/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_064 (Box 3)
      - Sealed Knot (GMA) (June 21, 22, 23 1981) (Separate Audio), 06/17/1981; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_065 (Box 3)
      - Still Photographers (A-Reel) (Edit Master) (Los Angeles 1984), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic SP, submaster, 10:00; bergman_p_066 (Box 3)
      - Still Photographers (B-Reel) (Edit Master) (Los Angeles 1984), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic SP, submaster, 10:00; bergman_p_067 (Box 3)
      - Still Photographers (Mix) (Edit Master) (Los Angeles 1984), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic SP, submaster, 10:00; bergman_p_068 (Box 3)
      - Still Photographers (Dub) (Los Angeles 1984), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic SP, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_069 (Box 3)
      - Still Photographers Profile (LA Olympics), 08/07/1984; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_070 (Box 3)
      - Still Photographers Profile (ABC Olympic Sports Coverage) (Sports Emmy Submission), 08/07/1984; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_071 (Box 4)
      - Super Bowl, 01/13/1984; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_072 (Box 4)
      - Trains (Weekend News), 04/01/1983; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 2:39; bergman_p_073 (Box 4)
      - Tuckins (Off Air Dub), 05/09/1980; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_074 (Box 4)
    - Individual Bergman stories (for various programs)
      - Advertising on TV, Parts 1-3 (World News Tonight) (Aired 3/14, 3/15, 3/16), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_075 (Box 4)
      - Advertising Series Promos, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_076 (Box 4)
      - Altmeyer/CIA, Parts 1-3, 03/07/1979; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_077 (Box 4)
      - Bennington Music Professor (GMA), 04/13/1982; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_078 (Box 4)
      - Birth Control, Parts 1-3, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_079 (Box 4)
      - Burning Questions Ethics, 06/02/1989; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_080 (Box 4)
      - Cow Billboards, 04/13/1984; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_081 (Box 4)
      - Crime/Farmer, Parts 1-3, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_082 (Box 4)
      - Drugs in America (JDS-13), 04/22/1988; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_083 (Box 4)
      - The Elderly, 06/07/1979; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_084 (Box 4)
      - Sub Reunion (GMA), 09/17/1982; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 10:00; bergman_p_085 (Box 4)
      - Young Handicapper (Koppel 2/14), 02/14/1976; Videotape, 2 inch videotape: Quad, dub, 3:30; bergman_p_086 (Box 9)
      - Health Care Costs, Parts 1-5 (World News Tonight) (Aired 2/5-2/9/1979), 02/05/1979; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_087 (Box 4)
      - Hill, Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 60:00; bergman_p_088 (Box 4)
      - Income Tax Series (Cordtz), Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 30:00; bergman_p_089 (Box 4)
      - Jimmy the Greek, 11/02/1968; Videotape, 2 inch videotape: Quad, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_090 (Box 9)
      - Jimmy the Greek Profile, Videotape, Betacam, dub, 90:00; bergman_p_091 (Box 10)
      - Jay Sarno Las Vegas, 11/25/1968; Videotape, 2 inch videotape: Quad, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_092 (Box 9)
      - Money Series. Parts 1-4 (Cordtz) (World News Tonight), 06/05/1979; Videotape, 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic, dub, 20:00; bergman_p_093 (Box 4)